tagdef.com 2017-11-13

# Privacy Statement | tagdef

This Privacy Policy Statement sets forth the privacy policy pertaining to this website, www.TagDef.com (the “Site”), which is owned by EMS Technologies, LLC (“TagDef”). By using this Site, you expressly accept and agree to be bound and abide by the terms set forth in this Privacy Policy Statement, and consent to the collection processing, storage and other uses of your information for the purposes and in the manner described below. For other terms and conditions that apply to your use of the Site, please review our Terms of Use. Any terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy Statement shall have the meaning given in the Terms of Use. This Privacy Policy Statement does not apply to the practices of third parties, including but not limited to, any third party websites, services and applications (“Third Party Services”). TagDef does not take responsibility for the content or privacy policies of those Third Party Services or the activities of any individuals that TagDef does not manage or employ. We encourage you to carefully review the privacy policies of all Third Party Services you access through TagDef.com and to be prudent with the information that you elect to share with others.

### **Collection & Use of Personal Information**

For purposes of this Privacy Policy Statement, “Personal Information” means any information you provide to us on or via the Site which can personally identify you, and may include your name, address, telephone number or e-mail address. As per our Terms of Use, this Site is not available to minor children (normally under 18 years of age); if we become aware that a minor child has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from our servers.  
TagDef uses your Personal Information only when you submit it to us, such as when registering for an account on this Site or when we respond to a question you ask or to suggestions or comments you email to us.

As a registered user, you can link your TagDef.com account to Third Party Services. In order to do so, you will provide us with your username or other user ID on each of the Third Party Services that you choose to link to. You may also be required to engage in an authorization process with each of those Third Party Services, where we receive a token that allows us to access those accounts so that we can, for example, when you choose, post your TagDef.com content, or links to your TagDef.com content, to those services. We do not receive or store your passwords for your Third Party Service accounts.

We do not sell or otherwise share subscriber lists or Personal Information. We may disclose your Personal Information to contractors and service providers only if and in so far as this is necessary for technical administration and maintenance of our Services. In addition, although we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose Personal Information when required by law or to comply with a judicial proceeding, a subpoena, a court order, or other legal process.  
Your Sharing of Information

Registered users of this Site will be able to share their Personal Information using certain features of the Services. In addition to postings that you publish as a TagDef.com user or using Third Party Services, please keep in mind that your content may be published in a manner which is subject to indexing by third  
party search engines. You should assume that anything you yourself publish will have a wide public audience, and that your published content may continue to exist and even be redistributed by others or retained indefinitely, including in our system servers, even if you terminate your account with TagDef.com.  
Non-Personal Information Collected

We collect information about how people use the Services offered on TagDef.com, but this information does not include any data that personally identifies you. Rather, this information includes general usage information, and may include information such as the number and frequency of our visitors, which pages or features of the Services they have visited, which links on the Services they have clicked on, and the length of those visits. We may also look for and tag keywords and subjects in user content, so that we can track interest levels of users and rank those interests. Additionally, we may collect information related to your location, such as by converting your IP address into a geographic location, as well as information related to your mobile device if you access TagDef.com in that manner, such as by converting the GPS signals sent by your mobile device or using sensor data from your device that may, for example, provide information on nearby Wi-Fi access points and cell towers. We may also use third party applications and services to collect and analyze this information. The information we collect in this manner enables us and third parties authorized by us to figure out how individuals use the Services so that we can analyze, improve and personalize them. Also, TagDef.com is a free service that is supported by advertising revenues. The collection of this information permits our advertisers to target ads to you that are relevant to your interests. Ad targeting is fully automated, does not involve information that personally identifies you and no humans read your content in order to target ads. Some of this information may be associated with the IP Address (as defined below) used to access the Services of the Site, and some may be associated with your registered account, such as the topics you search for and webpages that you visit or link to through your TagDef.com dashboard. We may also use some of this information in aggregate form as a statistical measure related to all of our users, and again this collection of data would not identify you personally. Information Collected Using Cookies: Cookies are pieces of text that may be sent to and saved by your web browser when you access a website; your web browser stores these cookies in a way associated with each website you visit, and you can see your cookies through your browser settings. We use cookies to enable our servers to recognize your web browser and tell us how and when you use the Services. Our cookies do not, by themselves, contain information that personally identifies you, and we don’t combine the general information collected through cookies with other such information to tell us who you are. However, we do use cookies to identify that you have logged in and that your web browser has accessed aspects of the Services, and we may associate that information with your account if you have one. This information, in turn, is sometimes used to personalize your experiences using the Services. Most web browsers have an option for turning off the cookie feature, which will prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your web browser software) allowing you to decide on acceptance of each new cookie in a variety of ways. While rejecting a cookie will not normally affect your browsing or your ability to access the features on our Site, you may be required to re-enter certain information you browse or when you return to the Site. Some Third Party Services that we use may also place their own cookies on your browser, and individual blogs on our network may contain code that places their own cookies. Note that this Privacy Policy covers our use of cookies only and does not cover the use of cookies by any third parties. Information Collected Using Web Beacons. We also may use electronic image requests (also called “web beacons” or “single-pixel gifs”) to count page views and to access cookies. The web beacons do not collect, gather, monitor or share any Personal Information; they are just used to compile anonymous information about Site usage.

### **Site Analytics**

TagDef may use a web analytics program or service that uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to analyze how visitors use a website. None of your Personal Information is used by any such program or service in making this statistical analysis for us.

International Users If you are located outside of the United States, please note that this Site is hosted on our computer servers in the United States. Therefore, your information may be transferred to and maintained in the United States, where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. Additionally, United States federal and state governments, courts, or law enforcement or regulatory agencies may be able to obtain disclosure of your information through laws applicable in the United States. Your use of this site or the Services or your submission of any Personal Information to us will constitute your consent to the transfer of your Personal Information outside of your home country to our servers.

### **Special Notes**

Modifications to this Policy: This Privacy Policy Statement is effective on June 15, 2017. If elements of our Privacy Policy change, we will modify this Privacy Policy Statement accordingly. You should check this page periodically for changes:www.TagDef.com/privacypolicy. Your continued use of this Site following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy Statement will mean that you accept those changes.

**Compliance** : If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, or if you believe that we are not following the policy as it is set forth here, you may contact us as follows:

Privacy Officer  
EMS Technologies, LLC  
Post Office Box 543  
Greenwich, CT 06836  
Fax to: (203) 569-2045  
Privacy@TagDef.com
